1997. New York City is a walled, maximum security prison.
Breaking out is impossible. Breaking in is insane.
Escape from New York is a science fiction, action
film directed by John Carpenter.
In a world ravaged by crime, the entire island of Manhattan has been
converted into a walled prison where brutal prisoners roam free.
After the US president crash-lands inside, war hero Snake
Plissken has 24 hours to bring him back.
Snake Plissken, played by Kurt Russell.
Police Commissioner Bob Hauk, played by Lee Van Cleef.
Cabbie, played by Ernest Borgnine.
President of the United States, played by Donald Pleasence.
The Duke of New York, played by Isaac Hayes.
Girl in Chock Full O'Nuts, played by Season Hubley.
Escape from New York is a 1981 American independent science fiction action
film co-written, co-scored, and directed by John Carpenter.
It stars Kurt Russell, Lee Van Cleef, Ernest Borgnine, Donald Pleasence,
Isaac Hayes, Harry Dean Stanton, and Adrienne Barbeau.
The film, set in a then-near-future world of 1997, concerns a crime-ridden United States, which has
converted Manhattan Island in New York City into the country's sole maximum security prison.
Air Force One is hijacked by anti-government insurgents who
deliberately crash it into the walled-off borough.
Former Special Forces and current federal prisoner Snake Plissken (Russell) is given just 24 hours to go in
and rescue the President of the United States, after which, if successful, he will be pardoned.
Carpenter wrote the film in the mid-1970s in reaction to the Watergate scandal.
After the success of Halloween (1978), he had enough influence
to begin production and filmed it mainly in St.
Louis, Missouri, on an estimated budget of $6 million.
Debra Hill and Larry J.
Franco served as the producers.
The film was co-written by Nick Castle, who played Michael Myers in Halloween.
Released in the United States on July 10, 1981, the film received positive reviews from critics
and was a commercial success, grossing more than $50 million at the box office.
The film was nominated for four Saturn Awards, including
Best Science Fiction Film and Best Direction.
The film became a cult classic and was followed by a sequel, Escape from L.A.
(1996), which was also directed and written by Carpenter and starred Russell.
The film explores themes of new york city, taxi,
martial arts, street gang, usa president.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking.